Happy Sabbath everyone.
Uh it is good to be here with you
today. Um I am uh thankful for the
invitation pastor and
um I am looking
forward to being fed the word of God
today because we're all going to eat.
Amen. Yeah. So, um I
uh you know technology is is something
else because as you all know I now have
an online church and uh what I did uh
this past
uh
Thursday was I pre-recorded my
message. And so I I'm I'm speaking live
at my church and they probably will not
know that I was not live until
afterward.
Um and I was trying to think what should
I speak, you know, what message should I
do here? I was like I'm not going to do
what I what I because you know I want to
do something different. But then as I
just uh as I thought about it more and
more,
um I'm going to be preaching now what
I'm actually preaching
now. So y'all caught that. I'm going to
be sharing the same message.
Um and and as I looked at your theme,
which is flourish,
uh what is it? Uh faith to fruit, right?
flourish faith to fruit. I thought to
myself, "Wow, Lord, you you really
orchestrated this." God. So, um, today
I'm going to talk to you about the
seal. The spirit. Come on now. And the
time of the end.
The seal, the spirit, and the time of
the end. So, let us pray. Heavenly
Father,
thank you,
Lord, for your amazing grace.
Lord, I ask that you would please speak
through me now and bless your people,
Lord, as we study, as we open the word
of God
together. May our hearts be
filled. May our
minds be rejuvenated
and may we walk away with a better
understanding of what it is you desire
of us. In Jesus' name we pray. Amen.
So in Daniel 12 and verse 1, the Bible
says, "And at that time shall Michael
stand up, the great prince, which
standeth for the children of thy people.
And there shall be a time of trouble
such as never was since there was a
nation even to that same time. And at
that time thy people shall be delivered,
everyone that shall be found written in
the book." How many of you want to be
found written in the book? Amen. And we
are told that a time of trouble is
coming. Uh and that time of trouble is
is really describing how God's people
will be attacked at the end of time. But
we don't need to fear because in
Revelation 7:1, the Bible says, "And
after these things, I saw four angels
standing on the four corners of the
earth, holding the four winds of the
earth, that the wind should not blow on
the earth, nor on the sea, nor on any
tree. And I saw another angel ascending
from the east having the seal
of the living God. And he cried with a
loud voice to the four angels to whom it
was given to hurt the earth and the sea,
saying, "Hurt not the earth, neither the
sea, nor the trees, till we have sealed
the servants of our God in their
foreheads." How many of you want to be
sealed with that seal? It is that seal
that will protect the people of God from
the attacks of the enemy particularly at
the end of time. And so the question we
have today is what is the seal? What is
the seal? Now I don't know if any of you
may be familiar with a little
controversy that is brewing as to what
the seal actually is because we have
typically held that the seal is what?
The Sabbath. But but some are saying,
"No, no, no. The seal isn't actually the
Sabbath. The seal is the Holy Spirit."
And so the question is, which one is it?
Which one is it? According to Ezekiel
20:12, the Bible says, "Moreover also, I
gave them my Sabbaths to be a sign or a
seal between me and them, that they
might know that I am the Lord that
sanctify them." So according to Ezekiel
20:12, the sign of God is what? The
Sabbath. However, there is also
Ephesians 4:30, which says, "And grieve
not the Holy Spirit of
God, whereby you are sealed unto the day
of redemption." According to Ephesians
4:30, it would seem that the seal or
even the sealer is the Holy Spirit
himself. Now why is this significant?
Because if the seal is the Holy Spirit,
if the sealer is the Holy Spirit, then
what he is sealing us with is his
character. And what is his character? It
is the fruit of the spirit. The fruit of
the spirit. So, could it be possible
then that what the enemy will be testing
at the end of time is your love,
your joy, your peace, your
longsuffering,
your gentleness, your goodness, your
faith, your meekness, your temperance.
Could it be that the devil might be
saying to God, "Remove the hedge and
allow me to test your people how much
they love one another. Come on now. How
much joy they have? how much peace they
have. Could it be possible that the
devil is saying, "I bet you that their
joy is only surface. I bet you that
their love is only service. I bet you if
I can get a group of people to attack
them that they will lose their peace,
that they will lose their patience." Are
y'all following what I'm saying? And so
the question again is, well, pastor,
which is it? Is it the Sabbath as we
have typically believed or is it the
fruit of the spirit? And that's what
we're going to talk about today. I want
you to notice with me. I want to deal
first with the fruit aspect. I want you
to notice with me Psalm chapter 1
beginning with verse one. The Bible
says, "Blessed is the man that walketh
not in the counsel of the ungodly, nor
standeth in the way of the sinners, nor
siteth in the seat of the scornful, but
his delight is in the law of the Lord,
and in his law does he meditate day and
night." His delight is in the law of the
Lord. But what is the law of the Lord?
It's the ten commandments. And so we see
here that the man who is blessed is the
man that is observing the law of God.
Amen. That points us to the Sabbath
which is the seal of the law of God. So
the question is settled except in the
very next verse we read, he shall be
like a tree.
There it is. I don't know if y'all
caught that just now. He shall be like a
tree planted by the rivers of waters
that bringeth forth his what? Fruit in
his season. His leaves shall not wither
and whatsoever he doeth shall prosper.
The ungodly are not. So So are y'all
following this? Yeah. It it appears that
the the blessed particularly at the end
of time are those who keep the
commandments of God, but they're also
described as a tree planted by a river
whose fruit will flourish. So the text
is actually letting us know that the way
that the fruit flourishes is that the
tree is planted by a what? A river. A
river of water. The tree is nourished.
The tree does not produce fruit by
itself. Are y'all with me? It produces
fruit as a result of being in a place
where there is a river that feeds the
tree.
There is water that is supplying the
tree. The tree does not make the fruit
on its own.
So the tree needs to be in a place that
is conducive to the growth of fruit. Are
y'all with me? All right. So, it seems
like, oh, well, pastor, then then yeah,
the the sealing then would be the seal
of the Holy Spirit. That is why we're
producing the fruit of the spirit. But I
want y'all to notice something else. How
many of you familiar with Isaiah 58?
Y'all know Isaiah 58? What chapter is
that? What's that talking about? It's
talking about the Sabbath, right? And
and and it's talking about how, you
know, the way that the Jews were
observing the Sabbath is not what God
wanted. But then he goes on to say that
this is the fast. This is what I want
you to do. And then he says something
that you're going to be like, whoa, wow.
Wait a minute. I get this now. Because
in Isaiah 58:1, the Bible says, "And the
Lord shall guide thee
continually. And satisfy thy soul in
what?
Drought. And make fat thy bones. And
thou shalt be like a
watered
garden and like a spring of water whose
waters fail not. Wait a minute. Do y'all
see what the Bible just did there? The
Bible just said that if you follow the
Lord and if you keep the Sabbath in the
way that he designed it to be kept, you
will be like a
watered garden. Now, why do you all want
to be like a watered garden? Why would
you want to be like a watered garden?
So you could flourish?
Because if you are a watered garden,
then you are flourishing in fruit. Fruit
is growing without your effort.
Did y'all catch it just now? But it's
interesting. It almost seems like the
Sabbath is tied in with the fruit of the
spirit. Because in order for the fruit
to grow, God says, "How you keep my
Sabbath, you will become like a water
garden,
a water garden who you you will be
satisfied in drought." Now, we know that
in a time of trouble, there's going to
be a drought. We know there's going to
be famine. Except for the people who
keep God's commandments, they will not
be in famine. They will be like a spring
of water or like a watered garden, like
a spring of water whose waters fail not.
You're going to be producing fruit even
when there is no water in other places.
Are y'all with me so far? So, so, so I
want to read to you Isaiah 61:1 in the
ESV version so that you can begin to see
how God throughout the Bible equates his
people to a garden. Notice what it says.
For as the earth springs forth, it
sprouts and as a garden causes, what is
sown in it to spring up? Come on now.
All right. Yeah. I don't know if y'all
caught that just now. As a garden
causes. Yeah. Let me ask how many of you
would like to produce fruit, good fruit,
love, joy, peace. How many of you try
real hard to produce fruit?
I I need y'all to understand this. The
text
says, "For as the earth bringeth forth
its sprouts and as a garden causes what
is sown in it to bring to spring
up
causes?"
Lord, I'm trying to produce fruit and
it's not working too well.
Could it be that it's because we're not
in the garden?
The text goes on to say, "So the Lord
God will cause righteousness and praise
to sprout up before all nations." So
what I'm trying to get you'all to see
here, beloved, is that God is describing
his people. He wants his people to be
like a well-watered garden. Now, here's
something interesting. In the book the
in the Song of Solomon, the Song of
Solomon, we know that there is a
bridegroom. Who does that represent?
Jesus. And then there is a bride. And
who does that represent? The church.
Notice what Song of
Solomon
4:12 says about the bride. Are y'all
ready? Are y'all sure y'all ready?
Listen to this y'all. Come on now. A
garden enclosed is my sister, my spouse.
A spring shut
up. A fountain se.
A fountain.
I'm waiting for y'all to help me. A
fountain sealed.
Sealed. Yeah.
Wait. God's church is like a Let me read
it in the
ESV. A garden locked is my sister, my
bride. A locked garden, a sealed
fountain. A locked
garden. H um John
Gil, scholar and commentator, what do
you have to say about this verse? Well,
John Gil says, "The illusion may be to
the sealed fountains. great personages
reserved for their own use. In other
words, only they had access to it.
Only they could drink from it. Come on
now. No one else had access to it. It
was sealed. Y'all not y'all not It was
sealed, locked up. No one else had How
about this? Adam Clark, what do you have
to say about this? And Adam Clark says,
"She is unsullied, a chasteed, pure
virgin. None has ever entered into this
garden. None has yet tasted of this
spring. The seal of this fountain has
never been broken. H a
virgin. A ver wait a minute. Isn't the
description of the
144,000 that they were
virgins? Are y'all following
this? It's as if God is saying to us,
"Listen, I want my people to be like a
well-watered garden that the devil
cannot get into.
It is producing fruit and the devil
cannot eat from it. It is producing
fruit and the devil cannot get in it to
destroy it to to corrupt it. These are
locked gardens, sealed gardens. And what
are these gardens doing? They're
producing fruit. Why? Because they're in
the garden is a river.
Hold on. Hold on. Hold on. Watch this
y'all. In the same chapter, Song of
Solomon chapter 4. in that same chapter
verse verse uh verse 13. So the very
next verse notice what it says next of
the bride. Thy plants are an orchard or
or an orchard of pomegranates with
pleasant fruits campfire and spikenard
spikenard and and saffron calamus and
cinnamon with all trees of frankincense
myrr and aloe with all cheese spices a
fountain of gardens a well of living
waters and streams from Lebanon. And now
notice verse 16. Awake, O north wind,
and come thou south. Blow upon my
garden, that the spices thereof may flow
out. Let my beloved come into his garden
and eat of his pleasant fruits. Wow.
Wow. Wow. Awake, O north wind, and come
thou south.
Awake, O winds, and blow. Y'all can blow
now because when you blow, all that's
going to happen is the fragrance of the
fruit. Uh, do y'all remember Revelation
chapter 7 where the four angels are
holding back the four winds. Those winds
are being held back from being blown
because God is saying, "Hold on. Wait a
minute. I've got to seal my people. I've
got to seal my garden so that when the
garden is sealed, when the winds are let
loose and the devil is doing everything
he can to destroy the people of God, all
it's going to do, all it's going to show
is the fragrance."
Are y'all catching this? The fragrance,
that's all these winds are going to
prove. The devil says, "Let me let the
winds go and and I will prove that that
they are not virgins. I will prove that
they are not lock gardens. I will prove
that they don't have fruit." But God
says, "No, no, no. When the l winds are
let loose, all that's going to happen is
the sweet fragrance."
The sweet fragrance. How many of you
want that sweet fragrance? Y'all listen.
Listen, this is why Jeremiah 31:12 in
the ESV says this, "They shall come and
sing aloud on the height of Zion. Their
life shall be like a watered garden, and
they shall languish no more." Listen,
now you begin to understand why in John
15:1, Jesus says, "I am the true vine,
and my father is the gardener."
My father is the gardener.
How many of you would like to have the
gardener work in your garden? How many
of you would like to have the gardener?
See, we're trying to do we're trying to
work on our own gardens. That's a word.
I I planted some love today. Well, well,
where's the where's the fruit? Well, it
takes some time, you
know, cuz we don't know what we're
doing. We're not gardeners. We can't
plant this kind of fruit. Only one can
plant the fruit and that is the heavenly
father. G this is why Jesus said remain
in me and I also in you. No branch can
bear fruit by itself.
Are y'all with me? So So we begin to
understand then that at the end of time
all the devil is seeking to do is attack
the sealed gardens.
He's trying to get in to the garden.
Now, beloved, we cannot do a study on
gardens without going back to the
original garden. I think y'all knew I
was going to go there, huh? We've got to
go back to the original garden. And and
here's something so powerful, beloved,
because in in Genesis 2 8 and 9, the
Bible says, "And the Lord God planted a
garden in Eden in the east, and there he
put the man whom he had formed." In the
creation, God put the man in the garden.
In the recreation, God put the garden.
God puts the garden in the man.
Did y'all catch that just now? In the
creation, he put the man in the garden.
In the recreation, if any man be in
Christ, he's a new creature. Old things
are passed away. Behold, all things are
become new. In the new creation, in the
recreation, he puts the garden in the
man.
So now beloved, you become this symbol
of what happened in creation week. So
for example, you might remember that
before you came to Christ, you were in
absolute darkness, but the spirit of God
moved upon the face of the waters and
God said, "Let there be light." Y'all
remember when light came to you? You
remember?
You remember when God pulled you out of
the waters, day two, baptism, a symbol
of rebirth. Do you remember that after
you were baptized, God began to bear
fruit in your life? Day three, the first
fruits came out of the ground. Day four,
the greater light and the lesser light.
God put a new light in your life, the
Bible and the spirit of prophecy. The
greater light and the lesser light. On
day five, God made you a fisher of men.
On day six, he says, "I'm recreating you
in my image and in my likeness." And so
when he was done with the creation, when
the garden was finished, he seals it.
Come on.
Yeah, he rests
from his work. His work.
Yeah, he seals it, beloved. He seals the
garden. Notice with me Genesis 1:31. And
God saw everything that he made, and
behold, it was very good, and the
evening and the morning were the sixth
day. So when when God gives the Sabbath,
watch this. When God gives the Sabbath,
it is a sign that showed that the garden
was working perfectly.
The garden was producing fruit.
The Sabbath was the sign that everything
was good. The garden was good. The
garden was producing fruit. So God seals
what is producing.
Yeah. Yeah. What is replicating?
So Genesis 2 verse one, thus the heavens
and the earth were finished and all the
host of them. And on the seventh day God
ended his work which he had which he had
made and rested on the seventh day from
all his work which he which he had made.
And God blessed the seventh day and
sanctified it because in it he had
rested from all his work which God
created and made. The garden was
perfect. Now why was the garden growing
fruit? I will tell you why. Because in
Genesis 2:10, the Bible says, "And a
river went out of Eden."
[Music]
A river went out of Eden to water the
garden.
Are y'all Are y'all Are y'all feeling
this? Are y'all catching this?
a garden a a river went out of Eden to
water the garden and from then it was
parted and became into four heads. So
y'all know the names of the rivers. The
first was Pyon verse 12 and the gold of
the land was good and the name of the
second river is Guehon and the name of
the third river is Ethiopia and and then
the last one I'm sorry is Hiddakel and
then the last one in verse 14 is
Euphrates. And I said hm I wonder if
these names have any meaning. And you
know what these names have meaning?
Would you like to know what they mean?
Here it goes y'all. Pyson means
increasing overflow. Gihon means gushing
forth. Hiddel means rapid. And Euphrates
means fruitfulness.
Hold on. Hold on. Could it be possible
that those who are dwelling in the
garden will experience an increasing
overflow, a gushing forth of rapid
fruitfulness?
Oh, no, no, no, no, no. Could it be
possible that those who are sealed,
those who are walking in the rest of God
will experience in their lives an
increasing, overflowing, gushing forth a
rapid producing of
fruitfulness. Wow. Wow. So the Sabbath
then listen, a working garden produces
fruit and this is what God seals. So the
question is, what does a working garden
look
like? What does a working garden look
like? Well, to find out what a working
garden looks like for us, all we need to
do is go back to Isaiah 58. You remember
that? Yeah. You remember how in Isaiah
58, God is saying, listen, y'all fast
for strife. You fast for this. And and
like that's not what I called you to do.
Right? And then he says then he says in
verse in verse 5, "Is is it such a fast
that I've chosen a day for a man to
afflict his soul? Is it to bow down his
head as a bull rush to spread sackcloth
and ashes unto him? Will thou call this
a fast and acceptable day to the Lord?
Is not this a fast I have chosen to
loose the bands of
wickedness to undo the heavy burdens to
let the oppressed go free and that you
break every yoke? Is it not to deal thy
bread to the hungry and that thou bring
the poor that are cast out to thy house
when thou seest the naked? That thou
cover him cover him and that you hide
not yourself from your own flesh?
Do you realize that to do these things
requires,
love,
joy,
peace,
longsuffering,
gentleness,
goodness, faith, meekness. It's as if
he's saying, "Listen y'all, the way that
I want you to observe the Sabbath will
be the very means of producing the fruit
you need to stand in the time of
trouble,
caring about others, helping others,
pouring out into others." It's literally
what the text says. And watch this. It
doesn't say to do it on the Sabbath or
just on the Sabbath. It means you're
doing it every other day of the week so
that when the Sabbath rolls around, God
says, "Here is the evidence that you've
had the fruit of the spirit growing in
you throughout the week." Word. Did
y'all catch that just now? You can come
to church every Sabbath and have never
kept a Sabbath.
That's what I'm trying to say. You could
come You You see, you spent the week
cursing people out. Come on. You spent
the week angry. You spent the week
without joy. You spent the week with all
those things and then you come to church
and you come to church happy.
Happy Sabbath. Yeah. God says you
haven't kept the Sabbath. The Sabbath is
the seal that you lived the week before
the way I asked you to. It's the seal
that the fruit of the spirit have been
flowing through you that you've been
living in the garden. And the Sabbath is
the seal, the sign of something. It is
not the thing itself.
Did y'all catch that? It is not the
thing itself. It is a sign of something
else. And what is that something else?
That something else is the fruit is
growing. The fruit is growing. So now
check this out y'all. Y'all never saw
this before. Y'all ready for this? Y'all
ready for this? Watch this y'all. In
Ezekiel 36, why do we go to Ezekiel 36?
Right? We go there to talk about the
what? Come on. Something that God says
he promises in Ezekiel 36. It's the new
heart, right? The new covenant. And we
know that the covenant is God writing
his law on our hearts, which is in
essence God sealing his people. Are
y'all with me? So, so watch this. Watch
this. In Ezekiel 36:28, here's what the
text says. And you shall dwell in the
land that I gave to your fathers, and
you shall be my people. Verse 27. I'm
sorry. Verse. No, no, no. I'm sorry.
Verse 24. Oh, 24. For I will take you
from among the heathen, and gather you
out of all countries, and bring you into
your own land. It's almost reminiscent
of God saying, I'm going to bring these
Israelites, these Israelites, these
tribes of Israel into their own land
symbolically. Think seal of God with me.
Think Revelation chapter 7 with me.
Notice what it says next. Then will I
sprinkle clean water upon you, and you
shall be clean from all your filthiness,
and from all your idols will I cleanse
you. A new heart also will I give you,
and a new what? Spirit will I put within
you, and I will take away the stony
heart out of your flesh, and I will give
you a heart of flesh, and I will put my
spirit within you, and
cause you
cause you to walk in my statutes, and
you shall keep my judgments, and shall
do them. How many of you would like to
be caused? Yeah. How many of you would
like to be caused? I was caused to do
this.
Why are you loving? So, I was caused to
do it. I was caused. That's a t-shirt. I
was caused. I was caused. I will cause
you. Right. And now notice verse 28. And
you shall dwell on the land that I gave
to your fathers, and you shall be my
people, and I will be your God. I will
also save you from your uncleanness, and
I will call for the
corn, and will increase it, and lay no
famine upon you, and I will multiply the
fruit of the
tree. Come on, y'all. The increase of
the field that you shall receive no more
reproach or famine among the heathen.
Thus sayeth the Lord, this is verse 33.
In that day shall I that I have shall
have cleansed you from all your
iniquities. I will also cause you to
dwell in the cities and the waste places
shall be built. Does Isaiah
58 you will be called the repairers of
the
breach, the restorer of the waste
places. Notice what the text says next.
And the desolate land shall be tilled.
And the desolate land,
the desolate land shall be tilled. Yes.
where whereas it lay desolate in the
sight of all that passed by. And they
shall say, can y'all read this with me?
Is it up on the screen? And they shall
say, read this with me y'all. The land
that was desolate.
Come on now. Is
become like what? The
garden. Do y'all understand that God is
trying to make us gardenarted?
That's what he's trying to do. He's
trying to make us
gardenarted. In Genesis 2:15, the Bible
says, "And the Lord God took the man and
put him in the Garden of Eden to dress
it and to keep it." Listen y'all, all
Adam had to do was to keep what God had
already provided. Y'all didn't feel
that. Y'all didn't Did you feel that?
Adam did not have to toil and sweat and
labor to keep because God had already
given it. So all Adam had to do was to
preserve.
Y'all y'all
All he had to do was preserve the fruit.
Are y'all following? That's all he had
to
do. It It's as if the garden was the
ecosystem for good fruit to grow.
God is trying to put us in an ecosystem
in which our fruit grows effortlessly.
But we all know the story, right? Adam
and Eve sinned. And when they sin,
when they sin, when they sinned, now in
order to produce fruit, they had to work
the toil in the sweat of thy brow.
Listen to me, y'all. Righteousness
should be no sweat.
Mercy.
Y did
y'all Let me Let me try that a different
way. Uh how else can I say I can't say
but any other way righteousness should
be no sweat
if you are working
to produce
fruit I'm working on this smile y'all
happy Sabbath all is well yes I love you
brother if you're working on joy and
peace and love it's It's a sign God is
trying to tell us. Listen y'all, it's
the sign that you're operating under
you're operating under the curse. You're
operating in the flesh. What I need you
to do is to go back to Eden.
What I need you to do is go to that
place where there is a river that that
produces that causes
fruit to grow. Because if you're working
to produce
fruit, if you're sweating to produce
fruit, something's not going
right. And you will fail over and over
and over and
over. Y'all understand that it is after
Adam and Eve sinned that the first
thorns and the
weeds and the
tears began to grow.
How are y'all doing so far?
What is the work of the flesh? Then the
text tells us the works of the flesh in
Galatians 5:19, the works of the flesh
are the which are manifest are these
adultery, fornication, uncleanness,
lasciviousness, idolatry, witchcraft.
Beloved, could it be possible that all
the mark of the beast, all the seal of
God is is showing who has the fruit of
the spirit, while all the mark of the
beast is is showing these are the people
that get angry easily, mercy, that will
kill. Yeah. That have no patience, no
mercy, no longsuffering. That's all it
is. And so for I think for a long time
we've just gotten caught up in if you if
you keep this day mark and if this day
is enforced uh if you keep this day seal
and this day mark when could it be that
God is saying no y'all these are just
signs of something much greater. Yeah.
You see beloved when a garden is kept
it's a garden but when it is left alone
it becomes a wilderness.
It becomes a wilderness. And what is a
wilderness? A wilderness is where wild
things grow.
[Music]
Are y'all Are you wild at heart,
pastor? I can't help you. And I'm just
wild at heart. I got to do my own thing.
I got to live my own way. How many of
you, beloved, are suffering from being
wild at heart? Don't raise your hand.
Don't raise your hand. So then, so then,
watch this, y'all. The the seal of God
is a reflection of those who are
gardenhearted while the mark of the
beast is a reflection of those who are
really deep down wild at hearts.
So the question
is when Adam and Eve sin, you remember
God put them out of the garden.
The plan of salvation is really then all
about how do we get back into the
garden. But remember when God put Adam
and Eve out of the garden, he put a
flaming
sword to keep the way of the tree of
life. Meaning the only way back into the
garden would have been through death.
Yeah. Yeah.
Hold on. Yeah. Take time. Take time. Do
Do you It's as if God is showing us,
he's using the garden and the wilderness
to teach us an object lesson of the work
he wants to do in us. So you remember
when the children of Israel were in
Egypt, right? They were in captivity,
bondage of sin, and then God comes to
deliver them and they cross the Red Sea,
a symbol of baptism.
And then where do they begin their
journey? The wilderness.
Where are they going?
What is the promised land about? It's a
land flowing with milk and honey. A
fruit
a fruitful land.
Beloved, watch this y'all. In the in
children of Israel's march from the
wilderness to the fruitful land, God is
so listen. Y'all are wild at heart. And
I'm trying to lead you from being wild
at heart to being gardenhearted.
In fact, when when when they send the 10
spies, the 12 spies, they go to check
out the fruit of the land and they come
back and say, "Man, we are able to go up
and possess this. Look at the fruit of
this
place." Where did Jesus start his
ministry?
Come on, y'all. Where did Jesus start
his
ministry? He started it in the
wilderness.
How long did the spies go out to spy?
You anybody remember? 40
days. And when they came back, they were
like,
"Yo, look at the
fruit." Jesus begins his ministry in the
wilderness. He's saying, "I'm coming to
the wild at heart. I have come for the
wild at." How many of you Let me ask the
safe question. How many of you have at
one time been wild at heart? That's a
safe question. If you at one I I didn't
ask you still now. I didn't ask. I just
said at that's a safe at one time. Amen.
You've experienced what it is to be
wild. Jesus said, "I've come for the
wild at heart."
And for 40 days, Jesus fasts and then he
overcomes the devil. And he's coming
back to us to say, "Look at the fruit.
Look at the fruit. Look at what can be
produced for those who trust in God. His
whole life was basically look at the
fruit. Look at the fruit. Look at the
fruit. Y'all y'all understand that God
is trying to show us something that I
think for many of us we have missed. His
whole life was the fruit. So now the
question again is how do we get back to
that place? How do we get into the
garden? Come on. Come on. John 12:24
Jesus says something very interesting
before he was going to die. He said,
"Verily I say unto you, except a corn of
wheat fall into the into the ground and
die, it abideth alone. But if it die, it
bringeth forth much fruit." Jesus is
talking about his own death. Are you
with me? So Jesus says, "Hey, I'm going
to die to bring forth much fruit." And
then Jesus dies. Anybody know where he
Jesus died?
Calvary. And then he's buried. Yeah. So
this Jesus who is a seed dies and is
buried. He's planted. He's planted. The
question is who planted him?
In John 19:41, I kid you not. Now in the
place where he was crucified, there was
a garden. Yeah.
And in the garden, a new supplicer
wherein man never yet. Listen. Jesus
dies and he's literally planted.
Come on y'all. He is planted in a
garden.
Now, now you remember that that that
that when Jesus resurrects, right, three
days later, and Mary goes, she's looking
for him, and then she she sees Jesus,
but doesn't know it's him, and she's
crying and and and uh Jesus saith unto
her,"Woman, why weepest thou? Whom
seekest
thou?" And the text says,
she supposing him,
[Music]
Oh, she's supposeding him to be the
gardener.
[Music]
Let me ask y'all a question, y'all. How
many of you would like the father and
the son as team gardeners?
She's supposeding him to be the
gardener. She supposed correctly. He was
the
gardener. And now he says, "Listen, for
those of you that want to follow me,
take up your cross and follow me." What
does it mean to take up your cross? It
means to die. The only way to get access
back into the garden to get access to
the tree of life,
the tree upon which Jesus died on. The
only way to get access back into the
garden is to die.
There you have it. There it is. There it
is. The mark of the
beast is the
symbol of those who do not have the
fruit of the
spirit. The seal of
God is the symbol that the garden has
been locked.
No one can get in.
It is God saying, "Shut the doors."
Y'all didn't catch that. You didn't
catch that. You didn't catch that.
Don't let anybody in.
And no one's going out.
God's people are locked in with him.
Shut the door. I I should have called
the sermon that. Shut the door. Can
y'all say it with me? Shut the door. God
wants the doors of his garden to be
shut, sealed, so that the enemy cannot
come in and God's people refuse to go
out. No, we're not going out. I'm not
going out like that. We're not going out
like that. And so, beloved, the mark,
listen, let me say it again. You can
come to church every seventh day and not
be keeping the Sabbath.
Let our prayer be,
Lord, teach me how to dwell in your
rest.
I I no longer want to struggle to
produce fruit. Cause me, Lord, to love.
Cause me. Let that be your prayer. I I'm
I will not toil in sweat any longer.
Lord, cause me. I'm here, Lord. Cause
me, please. That's my only prayer. Lord,
cause me to love. Cause me to have joy.
Cause me to have peace. Let it not be my
own. I have given you the Sabbath that
you may know that I sanctify you. You
cannot sanctify yourself. I sanctify
you. That's what the Sabbath is a sign
of. The devil thought he could sanctify
himself. So many of us think we can
sanctify ourselves. So many of us think,
"Hey, I can produce this fruit. Just
watch me." We got to get to the place
where we say, "Lord,
Teach me to rest.
Teach me to enter into your rest.
Hebrews chapter 3. Hebrews chapter 4.
Remember it was because they doubted the
fruit when they saw Joshua and and Caleb
saying, "Look at the fruit." And they
said, "Nah, we can't do that. We can't
get in
there." And it is that moment where God
said, "You shall not enter into my rest.
You all will die in the wilderness."
die in the where wilderness.
Lord, help us not to die in the
wilderness. Help us to live in the
garden. Thank you,
Father. Thank you for speaking to us
today. Lord, I'm making an
appeal and it is this.
There are people here who have been
working and toiling and sweating to
produce
fruit. And perhaps they didn't know,
perhaps they didn't
understand. But Lord, today they
understand that it is not about work, it
is about rest. Yeah. And that's why the
Sabbath is the perfect sign because the
Sabbath is the sign that the fruit is
being produced effortlessly.
Yeah, it is the sign that we are truly
resting in you and you are flowing
through us. The river of life is
producing the fruit. The fruit is really
there. We we are really acting upon it
but it is your work not ours. And so
Lord today there are
those who want to say I want to stop. I
want to stop
sweating. If that's your desire, I'm
going to ask you to just stand where you
are. I want you to even come down to the
front and we're going to pray a special
prayer. Lord, I'm
tired of
sweating. I want this fruit to be
produced to be caused. If that's your
desire, please just come meet me at the
front. And it doesn't have to be all of
you. I'm not asking everybody to stand.
I'm just saying you're convicted and
you're saying, "Lord, I'm
tired. Tired of toiling. I'm tired of
working under the
curse. Help me, help
me to
rest in you, heavenly
[Music]
father. Thank you for your amazing
grace. Thank you for your patience with
us. Thank you,
Lord, for showing
us that it is not about us. It is not
about our works. It is about your
work. You rested from your
work. Lord, we want to give
you the permission because of our
freedom of choice to work in us and then
be able to rest from your
work. Cause us, Lord. Produce that fruit
in us, Lord.
Let righteousness flow through us
naturally, not from ourselves, but from
your
spirit. Seal us and make us
gardenhearted. Remove the tears out of
our hearts. And may we be, as Isaiah 58
says, that wellwatered garden whose
springs fail
not. Thank you, Lord.
Thank you for hearing and answering our
prayer because we ask it in the precious
and holy name of Jesus. Let everyone say
amen and amen. You may be seated.
That was tough.
Like I